<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Ahmed Hasan</title>
    <link>https://aays.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Ahmed Hasan</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 21 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://aays.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Creating a New Theme</title>
      <link>https://aays.github.io/posts/creating-a-new-theme/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Sep 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aays.github.io/posts/creating-a-new-theme/</guid>
      <description>Introduction This tutorial will show you how to create a simple theme in Hugo. I assume that you are familiar with HTML, the bash command line, and that you are comfortable using Markdown to format content. I&#39;ll explain how Hugo uses templates and how you can organize your templates to create a theme. I won&#39;t cover using CSS to style your theme.
We&#39;ll start with creating a new site with a very basic template.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Migrate to Hugo from Jekyll</title>
      <link>https://aays.github.io/posts/migrate-from-jekyll/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Mar 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aays.github.io/posts/migrate-from-jekyll/</guid>
      <description>Move static content to static Jekyll has a rule that any directory not starting with _ will be copied as-is to the _site output. Hugo keeps all static content under static. You should therefore move it all there. With Jekyll, something that looked like
▾ &amp;lt;root&amp;gt;/ ▾ images/ logo.png  should become
▾ &amp;lt;root&amp;gt;/ ▾ static/ ▾ images/ logo.png  Additionally, you&#39;ll want any files that should reside at the root (such as CNAME) to be moved to static.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Recombination in the C. reinhardtii MT locus and consequences for selection efficacy</title>
      <link>https://aays.github.io/projects/mt-locus/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aays.github.io/projects/mt-locus/</guid>
      <description>‘Sex’ in C. reinhardtii is determined by a dimorphic, crossover-suppressed mating type locus, which encodes an individual as either MT+ or MT-. C. reinhardtii is isogamous (equal sized gametes) which means there are no sex differences; hence the term ‘mating type’. The two alleles of the MT locus can be thought of as ‘X and Y chromosomes’, except that each individual only carries one and that the alleles are genetically very similar.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Consequences of recombination for mating type evolution in C. reinhardtii - a summary</title>
      <link>https://aays.github.io/post/mt-locus/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aays.github.io/post/mt-locus/</guid>
      <description>Motivation Volvocine algae have been a model lineage for studying the evolutionary transition from isogamy (equal sized gametes) to anisogamy (unequal sized gametes). Instead of entire sex chromosomes, isogamous systems tend to have smaller and less differentiated mating type (MT) loci. Part of this putatively stems from these systems simply having less secondary sexual characteristics, and thus comparatively minimal need to segregate certain genes in one MT allele over another (under the sexually antagonistic selection model).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Recombination rate variation and linked selection in C. reinhardtii v2.0 - a summary</title>
      <link>https://aays.github.io/post/ld-paper/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aays.github.io/post/ld-paper/</guid>
      <description>In June of this year, I uploaded my first first-author (there has to be a cleaner way of saying that) manuscript to the preprint server BioRxiv. This was a huge and important milestone for me, and I was incredibly excited to have it out for the world to see virtually as soon as it was done &amp;ndash; such is the power of preprint servers!
Like in most endeavours in science, however, there&#39;s always room for improvement, and I&#39;ve been very fortunate to have gotten some thorough feedback from both members of my committee as well as other researchers in the community at large.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Migrating an Overleaf project to GitHub</title>
      <link>https://aays.github.io/post/migrating-an-overleaf-project-to-github/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aays.github.io/post/migrating-an-overleaf-project-to-github/</guid>
      <description>I&#39;ve been a big proponent of Overleaf for some time now, having written both committee reports and assignments in it to great success in my grad school career thus far. Recently, I expanded my horizons a bit and made my first conference poster in LaTeX &amp;ndash; something I admittedly found a bit head-spinning at first, but which eventually clicked just like everything else about LaTeX has in the past.
After returning from the conference (and recovering from a good bit of jet lag) I decided I wanted to preserve the project within a GitHub repo: code, plots, and all.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Recombination rate variation and infrequent sex influence genetic diversity in C. reinhardtii</title>
      <link>https://aays.github.io/projects/ld-paper/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aays.github.io/projects/ld-paper/</guid>
      <description>Recombination confers a major evolutionary advantage by breaking up linkage disequilibrium (LD) between harmful and beneficial mutations,thereby facilitating selection. However, in species that are only periodically sexual, such as many microbial eukaryotes, the realized rate of recombination is also affected by the frequency of sex, meaning that infrequent sex can increase the effects of selection at linked sites despite high recombination rates. Despite this, the rate of sex of most facultatively sexual species is unknown.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>hyde-hyde</title>
      <link>https://aays.github.io/projects/hyde-hyde/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aays.github.io/projects/hyde-hyde/</guid>
      <description>Hyde-hyde is a responsive Hugo theme inspired by @spf13&#39;s Hyde and its variant Nate Finch&#39;s blog. It was heavily restructured with modularised page layouts for easier maintenance and modification. Hyde-hyde offers awesome features such as nice colour tone, code highlighting, Font-Awesome 5&#39;s sidebar icons), a cool portfolio page, more choices for commenting (e.g. GraphComment, Disqus).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Setting up a simple cleanup log in bash</title>
      <link>https://aays.github.io/post/setting-up-a-simple-cleanup-log-in-bash/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aays.github.io/post/setting-up-a-simple-cleanup-log-in-bash/</guid>
      <description>A simple function to automatically append info about deleted files to a cleanup log!
Motivation (I originally wanted to just tweet this little trick out, but 140 characters is rarely sufficient for this sort of thing.)
Anyhow - sometimes, when dealing with large amounts of intermediate files in a project, it can be useful to log what&#39;s being deleted when and where. Here&#39;s a quick bash trick for setting up a function that logs a) which files where deleted, b) when they were deleted, and c) how much space was freed up as a consequence.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Endophytes as biocontrols for the Côte d’Ivoire Lethal Yellowing (CILY) disease</title>
      <link>https://aays.github.io/projects/cily/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aays.github.io/projects/cily/</guid>
      <description>As part of my undergraduate research work, I attempted to identify endophytic microbes that may potentially be used as biocontrols against the Côte d’Ivoire Lethal Yellowing (CILY) disease, which had previously destroyed approximately 350 ha of coconut trees in the West African country. This was done by creating profiles of the microbial communities present within both infected and uninfected trees. A ‘dilution-to-extinction’ method of high-throughput culturing was used in order to cultivate both bacterial and fungal endophytes directly from samples collected from the town of Grand-Lahou, followed by molecular analyses for strain identification.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>(Hu)go Template Primer</title>
      <link>https://aays.github.io/posts/goisforlovers/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Apr 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aays.github.io/posts/goisforlovers/</guid>
      <description>Hugo uses the excellent go html/template library for its template engine. It is an extremely lightweight engine that provides a very small amount of logic. In our experience that it is just the right amount of logic to be able to create a good static website. If you have used other template systems from different languages or frameworks you will find a lot of similarities in go templates.
This document is a brief primer on using go templates.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting Started with Hugo</title>
      <link>https://aays.github.io/posts/hugoisforlovers/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Apr 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aays.github.io/posts/hugoisforlovers/</guid>
      <description>Step 1. Install Hugo Goto hugo releases and download the appropriate version for your os and architecture.
Save it somewhere specific as we will be using it in the next step.
More complete instructions are available at installing hugo
Step 2. Build the Docs Hugo has its own example site which happens to also be the documentation site you are reading right now.
Follow the following steps:
 Clone the hugo repository Go into the repo Run hugo in server mode and build the docs Open your browser to http://localhost:1313  Corresponding pseudo commands:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>https://aays.github.io/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aays.github.io/about/</guid>
      <description>I’m currently a PhD candidate in Prof. Rob Ness’s lab at the University of Toronto Mississauga, trying to answer fundamental questions about how recombination rate variation impacts genome evolution using the model microbe Chlamydomonas reinhardtii. Although I dabble in wet lab work, my approaches are primarily computational. Most of my work is done in Python, R (I am an unapologetic tidyverse enthusiast), and the Unix shell/bash; I&#39;m passionate about programming in general, from both development and teaching perspectives.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CV</title>
      <link>https://aays.github.io/vitae/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aays.github.io/vitae/</guid>
      <description>Education   Ph.D. - University of Toronto Mississauga - 2017-present
 Computational &amp;amp; Evolutionary Genomics - Dept. of Cell and Systems Biology Supervisor: Prof. Rob Ness    B.Sc. (Hons.) - University of Toronto - 2012-2016 Majors in Human Biology, Cell &amp;amp; Systems Biology Thesis: Study of the endophytic bacterial and fungal communities inhabiting coconut palms infected by lethal yellowing-like phytoplasmas in Côte d’Ivoire. Supervisors: Prof. Keiko Yoshioka &amp;amp; Dr.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>